Edward Livingston Papers, 1683-1877 (bulk 1764-1836 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 1: Edward Livingston (1764-1836), 1781-1877; 1781-1836; 94 boxes
  - Subseries 1C: Papers Relating to the Penal Code, Criminal Jurisprudence, and Related Topics, 1784-1873; 1820-1836; 7 boxes
    - Writings, 1822-1825; 2 boxes
      - Book of Definitions (Draft), undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Penal Codes (Miscellaneous Drafts), undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Habeas Corpus Law (Drafts), undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Report on the Progress of the Penal Code (Draft), undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Act for Giving Effect to the System of Penal Law (Draft), undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Report(s) to the Senate and the House of Representatives Re: the Civil Code of Louisiana (Draft), circa 1823; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - An Act to Provide for the Erection of a Penitentiary and for Other Purposes (Draft), undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous Writings, undated; 6 folders (Folder 10-15)
      - Notes, undated; 9 folders (Folder 15-23)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 3 folders
      Contains extracts, articles, other miscellaneous manuscripts items.
      - Extracts and Articles Relating to the Penal Code, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Observations Relating to Penal Laws, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Printed Works by Edward Livingston, 1822-1872; portion of 1 box
      Arranged in chronological order by date of publication.
      - Rapport Fait a l'Assembly General de l'Etat de la Louisiane...d'un Code Penal, 1822; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - A l'Honorable Senat et a la Chambre des Representans de l'Etat de la Louisiane, 1823 February; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Etraits du Code Penal Projete, 1823; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - A System of Penal Law: Code of Procedure, Corrections and Definitions, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Letter from Edward Livingston to Roberts Vaux on the Advantages of the Pennsylvania System of Prison Discipline, 1828; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Remarks on the Expediency of Abolishing the Punishment of Death, 1831; 2 folders (Folder 9-10)
      - Expose d'un Systeme de Legislation Criminelle pour l'Etat de la Louisiane, 1872; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Works by Others, 1823-1873; 2 boxes
      Contains thirty-five books, pamphlets, and manuscript works by various authors, collected by Edward Livingston and other family members.
      Arranged chronologically, by date of publication, undated items at the end.
      - Bentham, Jeremy: Leading Principles of a Constitutional Code, 1823; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Hardie, James: History of the Treadmill, 1824; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Lewis, Seth: Structures on Dr. Livingston's System of Penal Laws, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Report from the Committee Appointed to Visit the State Prisons, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Report of the Commissioners for Building a State Prison at Mount Pleasant, 1826; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Speech of Mr. Thomson, 1826; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Lucas, Charles: Du Systeme Penitentiaire en Europe, 1828; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - The Second Annual Report of the House of Refuge, 1830; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - A View and Description of the Eastern Pennitentiary of Pennsylvania, 1830; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Mittermaier, Prof.: Considerationssur la Penitencier de Geneve, circa 1830; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Report of the Honorable S.M. Stilwell...on the Abolition of Capital Punishment, 1832; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Gilpin, Henry Dilworth: Review of Edward Livingston's System of Penal Law (Mss.), circa 1833; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Ducpetiaux, Ed.: Statistiques de la Peine de Mort, circa 1835; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Report Relating to Capital Punishment, 1836; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Lucas, Charles: Appendice a la Theorie de l'Emprisonnement, 1838; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Sarrut, G. and B. Saint Edme: Biographie des Hommes du Jour (A Biography of Charles Lucas), 1839; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Report in Favor of the Abolition of Capital Punishment Made to the Legislature of the State of New York, 1841 April 14; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Hello, J.: Notice sur la Colonie Agricole d'Essai du Val d'Yevre, 1850; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - A Charge Delivered by the Recorder at the Quarter Sessions for Birmingham, 1855; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Hello, J.: Des Colonies Agricoles Penitentiaires, 1865; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Compte Rendu par M. Hello...de l'Ouvrage de M. Mittermaier sur la Peine de Mort, 1866; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Hello, (J.): Notice Presentant par Ordre Chronologique le Releve et la Designation des Personnes et des Associations qui ont Pris la Part la plus Notable au Mouvement Abolitioniste de la Peine de Mort, 1867; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Lucas, Charles: La Colonie du Val-d'Yevre et la Petition au Senat Contre sa Production Horticole, 1868; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Societe de Patronage des Jeunes Detenus et des Jeunes Liberes du Department de la Seine, 1868; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Lucas, Charles: Rapport Verbal sur les Travaux de M. Mittermaier Relatifs a la Procedure Criminelle, au Droit Penal et a la Peine de Mort, 1869; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Lucas, Charles: De l'Abolition de la Peine de Mort en Saxe, 1869; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Lucas, Charles: De l'Abolition de la Peine de Mort en Portugal, 1869; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Observations Presentees a la Seance du 23 Avril 1870 par M. Lucas, 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Lucas, Charles: Lettre a M. Leonhardt... Relaive a La Troisieme Lecture du Project de Code Penal, 1870; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Lucas, Charles: Lettre a Son Excellence M. Le Compte de Bismarck...sur l'Abolition de la Peine de Mort, 1870; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Lettre de M. Ch. Lucas...a M. Van Lilaar...a l'Occasion du Project de Loi d'Abolition de la Peine de Mort, 1870; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Reforme Penitentiaire. Congress International, 1872; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Lucas, Charles: Observations Relatives au Congres Penitentiaire de Londres, 1872; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - Annual Circular of the Law Department of the University of Louisiana, 1873; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      - An Act to Amend Several Provisions of the Black Code, undated; 1 folder (Folder 21)
      - Notes Found with the Post-1836 Works by Others, undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Newspaper and Journal Clippings, 1825-1872; 4 folders (Folders 23-26)
      Includes several issues of Le Globe.
  - Subseries 1D: Miscellaneous Writings, 1792-1836; 1 box
    Includes masonic addresses, early political writings, translations, a notebook of letters written (1834-1836), a notebook of memoranda, and notes.
    - Writings, 1792-1806; 20 folders
      - Address on the Dedication of St. Johns Lodge (Masons), undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Address on the Installation of the Officers of Erin Lodge (Masons), 1802; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Address to the German Society, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Address to the Louisiana Lodge (Masons), circa 1805; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Address to the Public on the Academy of Arts, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Autobiographical Jottings, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Case of the OTSEGO Vote, 1792; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Deposition and Letters Re: Aaron Burr, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Experiments with the Steam Engine, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Report on a Professorship of Legislation, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - "Some pages of a novel...", undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Story called "Hans Menhaden" (Incomplete), circa 1806; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Tammany Letters to the Daily Advertiser, circa 1794; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - "To the Independent Electors of the City of New York", undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - "To the Independent Electors of the State of New York", 1792; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Translation of Justinian, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Translations from Cicero, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Translation of the First Chapter of Burlemaqui, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Translation on the death of Claudius, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Notes and Notebooks, undated; portion of 1 box
      - Notes, undated; 5 folders (Folder 21-25)
      - Notebook: List of Letters Written, 1834-1836; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      - Notebook, undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
  - Subseries 1E: Legal Records, 1785-1842; 6 boxes
    Contains personal legal files, papers relating to Livingston's run-in with General Wilkinson in 1806 and 1807, client casefiles and other legal papers.
    - Personal Legal Matters, 1803-1842; 1 box
      Contains correspondence, financial records, and legal documents such as depositions, affidavits, decisions, and powers of attorney. Of particular interest are the two folders of material which relate to the case of the United States v. Edward Livingston. The first part relates to the 1803 U.S. District Attorney affair; the second part relates to an 1840 attack on Livingston's reputation by Henry Clay, and subsequent rebuttals by Henry Dilworth Gilpin and John R. Livingston. There are also several cases relating to the New Orleans Batture. Correspondents include John D. Bechtel, Henry Carleton, Ogden Hoffman, and Francis Scott Key. See also series F. Financial Records: "Documents relative to my debts at New York", which also contains legal records.
      Arranged alphabetically by opposing litigant.
      - Joshua Armitage v. EL, 1822; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Executors of Abat v. EL, 1825-1836; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - EL v. Mary Brown and Others, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Richard Clague v. EL, 1806-1807; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - EL v. Dunham and Davis, 1805; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Flower v. EL, 1822-1837; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Heirs of Gravier v. EL (Batture), 1820-1825; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Hastie and Patrick v. EL, 1808; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Executors of B. Lafon v. EL, 1828; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - EL v. A. LeBlanc, 1814-1824; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Thomas Leggett v. EL, 1803-1809; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Thomas Lloyd v. EL, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - EL v. Claude de Lompre, circa 1813; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - EL v. Charles Lynch, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - EL v. Robert McClinnichan, 1820-1822; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Morton and Fitch v. EL, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - EL v. Pailette, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Edward E. Parker v. EL, 1820; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - EL v. Benjamin Story (Batture), 1825-1839; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - United States v. EL, 1803-1842; 3 folders (Folder 20-22)
      - Daniel Walden v. EL (Batture), 1823-1837; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      - William Wilkinson v. EL, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 24)
      - EL v. Joseph Winter, 1803-1812; 1 folder (Folder 25)
      - Micah Wright v. EL, 1810; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      - Miscellaneous, 1816-1831; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - General Wilkinson Matter, 1804-1809; 1 box
      Concerns General James Wilkinson's martial law rampage of 1806-1807, when he accused many persons, including Edward Livingston, of being party to the Burr Conspiracy, and also later charges against Wilkinson by the U.S. government. Contains correspondence, legal documents, drafts of Edward Livingston's memorial and speech, court records, notes, and printed items. Correspondents include James Alexander, Erich Bollman, Aaron Burr, Daniel Clark, Pierre Derbigny, Dominick A. Hall, Lewis Kerr, William Rogers, and James Wilkinson. See also Daniel Clark, Daniel Coxe, and Robert Goodloe Harper in Subseries 1A Correspondence: General for more discussion of the Burr Conspiracy and Clark's 1809 book Proofs of the Corruption of Gen. James Wilkinson.
      Materials also available on microfilm.
      - Letters of Wilkinson to Edward Livingston, 1804-1805; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1806-1807; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Legal Judgement and Burr letter, 1805-1806; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Copy of Letter of Burr to Wilkinson (in hand of Edward Livingston), 1806; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Edward Livingston's Address to the Public (draft and copy), 1806 December; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Edward Livingston's Memorial to the Legislature of New Orleans (draft), 1807 January; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Affidavit of Edward Livingston, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Note (in hand of Edward Livingston), circa 1806-1807; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Legal documents (Proceedings, Extracts, Affidavits), 1806-1807; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Legal Notes, circa 1808-1809; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Printed Items, 1808-1809; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Legal Files: Miscellaneous, 1785-1836; 4 boxes
      The files, which contain notes, court records, legal opinions, printed matter, abstracts, and some correspondence, does not reflect an original record group. It is composed of loose material and several different batches of similar documents. Some of these cases concern the New Orleans Batture. Of special note is the The U.S. v. Andrew Jackson. Also included in this grouping are several folders containing agenda, a notebook, miscellaneous (unidentified) material, and ledgers.
      - Files, 1785-1836; 3 boxes (1 partial)
        - Allard, Louis (Land Claims), 1827; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - A-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Barran adsm Territory of Louisiana, 1811; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Baudin, Alexandre - Estate of, 1803-1833; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Bastrop v. Wante, 1797-1837; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Birch, Thomas L. v. McMillan, John, 1804; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Blennerhasset, Harman, 1806-1813; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Breedlove v. Nicolet, 1832-1833; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Brown, Elijah v. New Orleans Insurance Company, 1808; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - B-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Callender v. Syndics of Grieve, 1811-1812; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Carrick v. Piernas and Wife, circa 1807; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Ship Cato, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - Chandler v. Trask, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        - City of New Orleans v. Territory of Orleans, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - City of New Orleans v. US, 1833; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Clark, Myra (Mrs. Whitney). Claims on Estate of Daniel Clark, 1835; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - Clay v. Smith, 1827; 1 folder (Folder 18)
        - Clay v. Creditors, 1821; 1 folder (Folder 19)
        - Conge v. des Bordes, 1814; 1 folder (Folder 20)
        - Cooley, Eben (Land Claims), 1827; 1 folder (Folder 21)
        - Cornell v. da Costa and the Spanish Government, 1812-1821; 1 folder (Folder 22)
        - C-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Dubourg, Heirs of v. US, 1833; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - D-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Forrestral v. Territory of Orleans, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Fulton, Heirs of, 1836; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - F-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Girard, Heirs of, 1835; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Gravier, John, 1807-1829; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Schooner Guia, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - G-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Hiriart, Sebastien, 1832; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Hospital de Charite de la Nouvelle Orleans, 1814; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - H-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - Jackson, Andrew (US v. Andrew Jackson), 1815; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        - Jackson v. Stiles, 1785-1797; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - J-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Keene v. US, circa 1808; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - K-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
        - La Croix v. Chamberlain, 1823-1836; 1 folder (Folder 19)
        - LaVillebeuve (Claims), 1803-1808; 1 folder (Folder 20)
        - Leonard v. Spanish Government, 1818-1830; 1 folder (Folder 21)
        - Life and Fire Insurance Co. of NY v. Adams, 1833; 1 folder (Folder 22)
        - Life and Fire Insurance Co. of NY v. Heirs of Wilson, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
        - L-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 24)
        - McCarty (Louisiana Land Claims), 1831; 1 folder (Folder 25)
        - Mericult, 1799-1819; 1 folder (Folder 26)
        - Montegut, undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
        - M-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 28)
        - New Orleans Navigation Company, circa 1811; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Norwood v. Le Blanc et. al., undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - N-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Ogden v. Saunders, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Orleans Bank, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Parsons v. Breedlove, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Planters Bank, 1813; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Poeyfare v. Sarpi, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - Phillips et. al. v. the Ship Pyomingo, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - P-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Ship Ranger, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Roberts v. the Brig Joseph Secunda, 1818-1821; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - R-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
        - Simonton, J.W. (Key West Claims), 1821-1835; 1 folder (Folder 14)
        - S-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
        - T-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - U-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - Valverde, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
        - Vermilya v. Nodine (and others), 1792-1793; 1 folder (Folder 19)
        - Voisin (Claims), undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
        - Walsh v. Antonio; Sedellin, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 21)
        - Wilkins, Thomas (Will), undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
        - W-Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      - Agenda, undated; 2 folders (Folder 24-25)
      - Notebook, undated; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
      - Record of Cases, undated; 1 folder (Folder 28)
        Ledger
      - Cases before the Superior Court of the Territory of Orleans, 1804-1807; 1 box
        Cash book ledger
  - Subseries 1F: Financial Records, 1783-1839; 2 boxes
    Consists of financial records for accounts, bonds, mortgages, checkbooks, and "Documents Relative to my Debts at New York."
    Arranged chronologically and by document type.
    - Accounts: General, 1783-1839; 2 boxes
      Contains a mix of professional and personal finances - receipts, accounts, bank protests, etc. Spotty representation, with many records for 1805 and 1836, in particular.
      - Accounts: General, 1783-1784; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Accounts: General, 1789-1792; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Accounts: General, 1793-1797; 2 folders (Folder 3-4)
      - Accounts: General, 1800-1803; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Accounts: General, 1804; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Accounts: General, 1803; 3 folders (Folder 7-9)
      - Accounts: General, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Accounts: General, 1807; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Accounts: General, 1808; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Accounts: General, 1809; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Accounts: General, 1810; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Accounts: General, 1811; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Accounts: General, 1812; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Accounts: General, 1813; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Accounts: General, 1814; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Accounts: General, 1815; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - Accounts: General, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      - Accounts: General, 1817; 1 folder (Folder 21)
      - Accounts: General, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 22)
      - Accounts: General, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      - Accounts: General, 1820; 1 folder (Folder 24)
      - Accounts: General, 1821; 1 folder (Folder 25)
      - Accounts: General, 1822; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      - Accounts: General, 1823; 1 folder (Folder 27)
      - Accounts: General, 1824; 1 folder (Folder 28)
      - Accounts: General, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 29)
      - Accounts: General, 1827; 1 folder (Folder 30)
      - Accounts: General, 1828; 1 folder (Folder 31)
      - Accounts: General, 1829; 1 folder (Folder 32)
      - Accounts: General, 1830; 1 folder (Folder 33)
      - Accounts: General, 1831; 1 folder (Folder 34)
      - Accounts: General, 1832; 1 folder (Folder 35)
      - Accounts: General, 1833; 1 folder (Folder 36)
      - Accounts: General, 1834; 1 folder (Folder 37)
      - Accounts: General, 1835; 1 folder (Folder 38)
      - Accounts: General, 1836; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Accounts: General, 1837-1839; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Accounts: General, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Bonds, 1794-1823; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Mortgages, 1798-1838; 3 folders (Folder 5-7)
    - Checkbook, 1836; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - "Documents Relative to my Debts at New York", 1797-1808; 7 folders (Folder 9-15)
      These records were found together in a bundle labeled as above. Contains notes, bonds, legal documents, accounts and some correspondence. Similar material can also be found in series E.1 Personal Legal Matters.
  - Subseries 1G: Wills, Inventories, and Miscellaneous Estate Papers, 1803-1836; 5 folders
    Includes a catalogue of books owned by Livingston, and an inventory of the contents of Montgomery Place.
    Arranged as ordered in series title.
    - Wills, 1828-1835; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Inventories, 1819-1836; portion of 1 box
      - Contents of Apartment, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Catalogue of Books Owned by Edward Livingston and an Agreement with James Workman, 1823; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Inventory of Contents - Montgomery Place, 1836; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1803-1836; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Subseries 1H: Certificates, Awards, Degrees, Honors, and Official Documents, 1781-1836; 1 box
    Includes Livingston's diploma from the College of New Jersey (1781), law licenses, honorary memberships, appointments to career posts, masonic certificates, etc.
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1781-1836; 31 folders (Folder 1-31)
      Arranged chronologically, by year.
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1781; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1785; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1787; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1790; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1793; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1795; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1797; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1801; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1801-1802; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1803; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1804; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1805; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1808; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1813; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1814; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1821; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1822; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1823; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1824; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1825; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1826; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Certificates, Awards, Etc., 1827; 1 folder (Folder 22)